<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Sudarshana A</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Sudarshana A</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>MINETEST Game</title>
      <link>/post/2018-09-02-minetest-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-09-02-minetest-game/</guid>
      <description>Minetest is similar to Minecraft. I want to install Minecarft for Linux and did some research. Accidentally I found out about the Minetest, an open source game similar to Minecraft.
I have installed it to my laptop running Ubuntu 18.04.1 LTS. Tutorial for Minetest beginers can be found here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub changes - user name</title>
      <link>/post/2018-08-14-github-changes-user-name/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-08-14-github-changes-user-name/</guid>
      <description>I have changed my GitHub user name to more meaningful name. 😃
 What happens when I change my username?
 Also spent some time to clean up my GitHub account and set up all the remote links to the repositories.
First I have listed my existing remotes to get the names
e.g.
go to the local repository folder and run the command git remote -v
$ git remote -v origin	https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Personal Blog using Blogdown</title>
      <link>/post/2018-08-09-new-personal-blog-using-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-08-09-new-personal-blog-using-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>Past few days I was busy with DataCamp lessons and not much time for write something new. I have transfred by previous blog entries(SnD Creations) to new repository and used blogdown with beautifulhugo theme.
Several Hugo themes have been used beofre selecting beautifulhugo theme. I want somehting similar to bootstrap with fixed navigation bar, plus support for Math.
Thanks to blogdown book from Yihui Xie, finally I have re-launched the site using blogdown &amp;amp; Hugo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keyboard Backlight - Dell - Ubuntu</title>
      <link>/post/2018-05-20-ubuntu-dell-backlight/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-05-20-ubuntu-dell-backlight/</guid>
      <description>I have realised my Dell laptop keyborad backlight doesn&amp;rsquo;t light up in Ubuntu. So did some browsing and changed the config file.
 Set the brightness level to &amp;gt; 0 using below, you need to change the value using super user (or root). Open the config using nano editor.  sudo nano /sys/devices/platform/dell-laptop/leds/dell\:\:kbd_backlight/brightness change the value 0, I have changed it to 2, then save the config.
 Also if required we can set the timeout of the keyboard backlight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installed CherryTree</title>
      <link>/post/2018-03-28-install-cherry-tree/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-03-28-install-cherry-tree/</guid>
      <description>To day I have installed CherryTree. Nice note taking application. You can download CheeryTree from here. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Set up local copy of site</title>
      <link>/post/2018-03-24-install-local-copy-of-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-03-24-install-local-copy-of-site/</guid>
      <description>To day I have installed a local copy of this web site. Using Jekyll. I have refered Setting up your GitHub Pages site locally with Jekyll for that.
As per the instruction below command used for check the Ruby version.
ruby --version I had to installed Ruby, then bundler but after completting most of the items, an error message popped up in the terminal.
 Failed to build gem native extension&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Probability with R programming project</title>
      <link>/post/2018-03-23-simple-probability/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-03-23-simple-probability/</guid>
      <description>Add more functinality to my simple probability R markdown files. Used dplyr and tidyr packages to arrange data.
But later I have changed the code so that most of the data was arranged using base R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lets Try Sinhala | අපි සිංහල ලියමු !</title>
      <link>/post/2018-03-04-lets-try-sinhala/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-03-04-lets-try-sinhala/</guid>
      <description> I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find Sinhala key input system like Sri Shell. So I had a chat with the person who developed the Sri Shell. He told me to use Google Input.
So I tried using Google Sinhala Input
Sinhala Input සිංහල ලිවීම හරිම ලේසියි . මෙන්න මෙහෙමයි . </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installed Ubuntu 17.10</title>
      <link>/post/2018-03-03-ubuntu-installed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-03-03-ubuntu-installed/</guid>
      <description>To day I have installed Ubuntu 17.10 on new laptop. Also installed RStudio, Git and tried Scratch, but Scratch is an old version so uninstalled that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tried Ubuntu 17.10</title>
      <link>/post/2018-03-01-ubuntu-tried/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-03-01-ubuntu-tried/</guid>
      <description>To day I have tried Ubuntu 17.10 on new laptop. Previously tried the Ubuntu 16.04. Seems fine to install it along side with Win7. I bought new (actually it is not new, bought it 2nd hand laptop via ebay.) laptop. It supposed to come without OS but new copy of OEM windows 7 already there. 😃</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning and Testing GIT</title>
      <link>/post/2018-02-25-learning-and-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-02-25-learning-and-testing/</guid>
      <description>Today I played around with GitHub and installed Git for windows. Changed my commit email and used noreply email generated by GitHub.
GIT Bash Also used Git Bash..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SnD Creations, Launches Site</title>
      <link>/post/2018-02-15-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-02-15-first-post/</guid>
      <description>Well. Finally got around to putting this. Neat thing about it - powered by Jekyll and I can use Markdown to author my posts. It actually is a lot easier than I thought it was going to be.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>